YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 10. Audiovisual Materials
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. VIDEOTAPES
  - Videotapes-Originals DO NOT USE, [see boxes 1111 and 1112 for Use Copies]
    - Trip to South Africa: Gwendolyn Baker, Ann Stallard, Nelson Mandela, photographic prints transferred to video, Apr 1993, Umatic and VHS (Box 1098, Folder 7-8)
    - Mid-Triennial Conferences,Apr 1993
      - "Mid-Triennial Program Tape" visual program tape for use at conferences, edited master, Umatic and VHS (Box 1098, Folder 9-10)
      - "The Convention Process, a 3-Year Cycle," visuals for live narration/speaker support, edited master, MBR 20s and VHS, Apr (Box 1098, Folder 11-12)
      - Raw footage, 2 Apr (Phoenix?), Umatic (Box 1098, Folder 13-16)
      - Ann Stallard opening remarks, VHS (Box 1098, Folder 17)
      - A Dialogue: "Leadership for Change: Past, Present, Future" with Ann Stallard, Norma Sims, Mildred Morrison, and Kristi Adams, master edit, Umatic and VHS (Box 1098, Folder 18-19)
      - Oral History: "A Dialogue: Leadership for Change; Past, Present, and Future with Vivian Grove and Louise Hendrickson, 1993, Umatic, VHS (Box 1098, Folder 20-21)
      - Session on the 135th Anniversary, 4 Apr, Umatic (Box 1099, Folder 1-3)
      - Opening and Closing photo montages with music, Spring 1993, VHS * (Box 1099, Folder 4)
      - Slide transfer of Mid-Triennial Conference in Raleigh, NC, MBR 20s (Box 1099, Folder 5)
      - Slide transfer of scenes Mid-Triennial Meeting and 1992 Cycle Meeting in Phoenix, MBR 20s (Box 1099, Folder 6)
    - WBFF (Fox) News at Ten, Baltimore news story re launch of YWCA CDC partnership and ENCOREplus, 3 May 1993,VHS (Box 1099, Folder 7)
    - KPHO-TV, Channel 5 news story on the 135th anniversary YWCA, 14 May 1993, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 8)
    - Exercise videotape for women who have undergone breast cancer surgery, 18 May 1993, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Senate Hearing on Reauthorization of the Breast and Cervical Cancer Mortality Act, YWCA among witnesses, 15 Jul 1993, VHS* (Box 1099, Folder 10)
    - YWCA logo (looped for 5 minutes), produced Oct 1993; no audio, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 11)
    - 135th Anniversary historical slides, October 1993, Umatic and VHS * (Box 1099, Folder 12-15)
    - "YWCA of the USA Convention Kaleidoscope, Atlanta, 1991," produced 26 Oct 1993, Umatic (Box 1099, Folder 16)
    - New York Good Day news magazine story re NY City 135th Anniversary Gala, 27 Oct 1993; and WUSA-TV Eyewitness news coverage of Janet Reno appearance at opening of 135th Anniversary exhibit at the National Museum of Women in the Arts, Washington, DC, 28 Oct 1993, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 17)
    - "YWCA of the U.S.A.--Year in the Making," compilation of television and press coverage, 28 Oct 1993, Umatic, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 18-19)
    - Leadership Development Center, promotional video, 1994, VHS (Box 1099, Folder 20)
    - YWCA Retirement Fund: "Guardian Spirits", 1 Feb 1994, VHS * (Box 1099, Folder 21)
    - KPHO-TV Channel 5, Phoenix, AZ, news story re 135th Anniversary Exhibit opening at the Leadership Development Center and the 10th Anniversary of LDC, 5 Feb 1994, VHS (Box 1100, Folder 1)
    - "Taggable" Public Service Announcement in the Lifetime Television "Picture What Women Do" series featuring the YWCA, 25 Feb 1994, VHS (Box 1100, Folder 2)
    - Prema Mathai-Davis: A Portrait, photo montage and narration, 17 Mar 1994, Umatic (Box 1100, Folder 3)
    - Convention Preparation Meeting Videoconference, 1994
      - Rehearsal, Feb 1994,Umatic (Box 1100, Folder 4)
      - Video segment inserts (includes LDC promo), 18 Mar 1994, Umatic (Box 1100, Folder 5)
      - "1994 CPM Video Conference," distributed to all Associations, 31 Mar, VHS (Box 1100, Folder 6)
    - Public Service Announcements produced by Louis London (featuring YWCA historical photographs), Feb-Nov 1994, Beta, Umatic dubbing master, and VHS * (Box 1100, Folder 7-10)
    - "Partnership Evaluation," with Inca Mohamed and Pam Garza, [probably Youth Development], 3 Mar 1994, Umatic (Box 1100, Folder 11-16)
    - "Putting Women First for 135 Years," 18 minute video for 135th Anniversary, Apr 1994, Umatic edited version and dubbing master, and VHS * (Box 1100, Folder 17-19)
    - "Tree of Life Promo/PSA" 30 second public service announcement "promoting donation to the Tree of Life for special recognition of Associations, special persons, special events," Apr 1994, Umatic (Box 1100, Folder 20)
    - 33rd National Convention (Los Angeles), 22-26 Jun 1994
      - Plenary, Wednesday, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 1)
      - Plenary, Thursday, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 2)
      - Plenary, Friday, Racial Justice Lunch, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 3)
      - Plenary, Friday, part 2, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 4)
      - Plenary, Sunday, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 5)
      - "Priority" rap video of women, UCA10s and Beta (Box 1101, Folder 6-7)
    - "YWCA Interview,"12 Sep 1994, Umatic (Box 1101, Folder 8)
    - Video about Lillian Kimura for the New Jersey Women's Summit, Oct 1994
      - Final video, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 9)
      - Lillian Kimura photos, part 1, covershots, Umatic (Box 1101, Folder 10)
      - Lillian Kimura photos, part 2, concentration camp photos,Umatic (Box 1101, Folder 11)
    - Television coverage of Avon's Breast Cancer Awareness Crusade, CBS "This Morning," 6 Oct 1994, and ABC "Good Morning America," 7 Oct 1994, VHS (Box 1101, Folder 12)
    - World YWCA Centenary Service, Cathedral Church of St. John and St. Peter [Washington National Cathedral], 16 Oct 1994
      - Raw footage, tapes 1A-5A and 1B-3B, Umatic (Box 1101, Folder 13-20)
      - Raw footage, Beta copy, tapes 4B-5B (Box 1101, Folder 21-22)
      - Edited, Umatic and VHS * (Box 1102, Folder 1-2)
    - ENCOREplus Training, 12 Dec 1994
      - Component 1 Medical Lecture, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 3)
      - Component 2 Medical Lecture, Dr. David Riseberg, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 4)
    - Hillary Rodham Clinton message to the YWCA of Greater Atlanta Salute to Women of Achievement luncheon, 1995, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 5)
    - "An Uncommon Vision" training video re the One Imperative produced by the YWCA New Castle County (Delaware), 1995, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 6)
    - "Talk it Over" show on Lifetime Television, program on violence featuring Project Protect at the YWCA of Eastern Union County, New Jersey, 1995, VHS * (Box 1102, Folder 7)
    - Strategic Planning Initiative, Strategic Planning Forums '95 Round 2
      - Raw footage, Forum in Phoenix, 6 Feb 1995 (Box 1102, Folder 8-9)
      - "Strategic Planning Forum '95, Round 2," videotape distributed to Host Associations for use if weather prevented national leadership from getting to the Forum, produced on 11 Feb using footage from 6 Feb Forum in Phoenix, Umatic and VHS * (Box 1102, Folder 10-11)
    - World YWCA Centenary, 17 Apr 1995, Beta (Box 1102, Folder 12)
    - Strategic Planning Committee Meeting, 19 May 1995, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 13)
    - Social Security Seminar, 1 Jun 1995, Umatic (Box 1102, Folder 14-18)
    - Compilation of YWCA television coverage6 Jun 1995: Prema Mathai-Davis at NOW March; Week without Violence kick off press conference; ABC "Person of the Week," Susan Kelley of the YWCA of Topeka, Kansas, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 19)
    - YWCA of Spokane, Washington, ENCOREplus Public Service Announcement, 13 Jun 1995, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 20)
    - Today Show segment on "Week Without Violence," press conference in Los Angeles, 19 Jun 1995, VHS (Box 1102, Folder 21)
    - The Strategic Plan, Jul 1995, Umatic (Box 1102, Folder 22)
    - World YWCA Council, 6-13 Jul 1995 (Box 1103)
      - "Pics," Set 1 "95", 1995 - Umatic (Box 1103, Folder 1)
      - "Pics," Set 2 "95", 1995 - Umatic (Box 1103, Folder 2)
    - Strategic Planning Initiative, Ambassador Training, 4 Aug 1995, Umatic and VHS (Box 1103, Folder 3-8)
    - "New York Undercover" episode called "Student Affairs" featuring a character wearing a YWCA Week Without Violence T-Shirt, copyright Universal Studios, 11 Sept 1995, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 9)
    - Hillary Rodham Clinton Public Service Announcement for YWCA Week Without Violence, Oct 1995, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 10)
    - YWCA ENCOREplus Program, "Year 1 Review," 4 Oct 1995, Beta and VHS (Box 1103, Folder 11-12)
    - Service for 'A Day of Remembrance' in the Week Without Violence, Cathedral of St. John the Divine, NYC,15 Oct 1995
      - Service, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 13-14)
      - Excerpt including sermon by Prema Mathai-Davis, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 15)
    - Women's Vote Project '96 Public Service Announcement "Empowerment," 17 Oct 1995, VHS * (Box 1103, Folder 16)
    - Television news coverage of Violence Against Women Rally Sponsored by the YWCA, New Jersey Network News and NBC Nightly News, 18 Oct 1995, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 17)
    - WRAL-TV interview re YWCA of Wake County (North Carolina) ENCOREplus Program, 19 Oct 1995, VHS (Box 1103, Folder 18)
    - New Face of Fitness Program, Train-the-Trainer Workshop, 28-30 Oct 1995
      - VHS (incomplete) (Box 1103, Folder 19-22)
      - Umatic tapes 1 and 2 (Box 1103, Folder 23-24)
      - Umatic tapes 3 through 12 (Box 1104, Folder 1-8)
    - WBNG-TV Channel 12 "Med Break" story re the ENCOREplus Program at the YWCA of Binghamton/Broome County (NY), 20 Nov 1995, VHS (Box 1104, Folder 9)
    - Louise R. Fawcett's Farewell party at CIII Restaurant, 5 Dec 1995, VHS (Box 1104, Folder 10)
    - The State Funeral of Her Excellency Dame Nita Barrow, Governor General Barbados, edited version, unedited version, and tributes, 29 Dec 1995, VHS (Box 1104, Folder 11-12)
    - "The Bubble Monster and other science fun," YWCA of Annapolis and Anne Arundel County, Adult version and Teen age baby sitter version, 1996, VHS (Box 1104, Folder 13-14)
    - "Dialogue with Laurel Vlock" television program re YWCA with Vivian Manning Fox and Jean W. Schoonover of the YWCA of the City of NY, 1996, VHS (Box 1104, Folder 15)
    - "The First YWCA Week Without Violence," re the 1995 campaign, 1996, VHS* (Box 1104, Folder 16)
    - "Newstalk Television," Cable news program on guns, Prema Mathai-Davis as panelist, 1996, VHS * (Box 1104, Folder 17-18)
    - Women's Vote Project '96 short television spot for Iowa, Lifetime Television, circa 1996, VHS * (Box 1104, Folder 19)
    - "YWCA The Lives We Touch," YWCA of Cincinnati, 1996 (Box 1104, Folder 20)
    - Cancer Information Service 20th Anniversary San Francisco, Tapes 5-6, 25 Mar 1996, Beta (Box 1104, Folder 21-22)
    - "The Imperative is Now! Legacy of a Movement," Convention preparation video, Apr 1996, VHS * (Box 1104, Folder 23)
    - YWCA ENCOREplus Program, "Program Review" Re-editing from Dubbing Master, 16 May 1996, Beta (Box 1104, Folder 24)
    - 34th National Convention(Jun 1996)
      - ISO tapes, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 1-15)
      - EP tapes, VHS * (Box 1105, Folder 16-20)
      - Mission Plenary: Panel on Heterosexism, 7 Jun, VHS * (Box 1105, Folder 20a)
      - Ellen Craft Dammond, [oral history?] St. Louis Marriott, Umatic (Box 1105, Folder 21)
      - Ann Stallard, compilation of speeches and presentations prepared for Convention, 1996
        - Unedited footage, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 22-23)
        - "YWCA Redo Convention 1996," final version, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 24)
    - YWCA Opening logo animation, 18 Sep 1996, Beta (Box 1105, Folder 25)
    - "Big Help Spot" Big Help story during Nickelodeon Television Big-Help-a-Thon, 19 Sep 1996 re an Illinois YWCA group project, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 26)
    - President Bill Clinton Public Service Announcements for Week Without Violence, Redesign, 30 Sep 1996, Original and re-edited versions, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 27-28)
    - Public Service Announcement, YWCA of Topeka, Week Without Violence, 2 Oct 1996, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 29)
    - USA Network Public Service Announcements for "Erase the Hate" campaign, YWCA Week Without Violence, 6-12 Oct 1996, VHS* (Box 1105, Folder 30)
    - "Charlie Rose" television program re Week Without Violence, 9 Oct 1996, Beta (Box 1105, Folder 31)
    - YWCA of West Palm Beach County Week Without Violence panel at Roosevelt [High School?] re Eliminating Racism and Hate Crime, 11 Oct 1996, VHS (Box 1105, Folder 32)
    - "Erase the Hate," USA Network special aired during Week Without Violence, 11 Oct 1996, VHS * (Box 1105, Folder 33)
    - "Open Air Opens Minds" transition to high school program run by the YWCA of Wheeling, WV, and the Black Diamond Girl Scouts, 17 Jan 1997, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 1)
    - Nickelodeon Television "Big Help" coverage of the Presidents' Summit for America's Future, Apr 1997, VHS * (Box 1106, Folder 2)
    - President Bill Clinton Public Service Announcement for YWCA Week Without Violence, October 1997, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 3)
    - Nickelodeon Television "Big Help-a-Thon '97" Partner Challenge Tape, [YWCA a partner], 8 Oct 1997, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 4)
    - "The Imperative is Now, A Panel Discussion on Race and Race Relations," third draft, 16 Dec 1997, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 5)
    - 11th Annual Black History Teleconference: "The Struggle Continues," South Carolina Educational Television, [YWCA a co-sponsor], 1998, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 6)
    - "The Imperative is Now: A Panel Discussion on Race and Race Relations," final version, 28 Jan 1998, VHS * (Box 1106, Folder 7)
    - "The National Hate Test," USA Television special premiering in conjunction with the National Erase the Hate and Eliminate Racism Day, 30 Apr 1998, VHS * (Box 1106, Folder 8)
    - YWCA Race Against Racism, 7 minute promotional video, 8 Jun 1998, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 9)
    - "Caring for Kids Our Lifetime Commitment," Lifetime Television year-long campaign advocating for child care: compilation reel, [YWCA a co-sponsor], 30 Jun 1998, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 10)
    - YWCA National Board's Recommended National Dues Formula, Jul 1998, VHS * (Box 1106, Folder 11)
    - Race Against Racism, television news coverage, Washington, DC, 1 May 1999, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 12)
    - YWCA: 3rd Race Against Racism, 5 minute, 30 second promotional video, 9 Jun 1999, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 13)
    - "I'm Not a Racist, But…Small Steps Toward Healing the Hate," Lifetime Television panel with Prema Mathai-Davis, 24 Oct 1999, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 14)
    - President Bill Clinton Public Service Announcements for YWCA Stop Racism Youth Challenge, 2000, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 15)
    - YWCA National Board Meeting, Phoenix, AZ, 24-25 Feb 2000, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 16-20)
    - "Hidden Victims: Children of Domestic Violence," Lifetime Television program with segment on Annapolis and Anne Arundel County YWCA program, 6 Nov 2000, VHS * (Box 1106, Folder 21)
    - 36th Convention, 2001
      - 12 Jul, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 22-24)
      - 13 Jul, VHS (Box 1106, Folder 25-30)
  - Undated Videotapes
    - "Alexine Clement Jackson YWCA," n.d., Umatic (Box 1106, Folder 31)
    - "Ann Nichols," n.d., Umatic (Box 1106, Folder 32)
    - "Ann" [Stallard?], n.d., Beta (Box 1106, Folder 33)
    - "Aquatics Risk Management: YWCA Pool Safety," training session, n.d., VHS (Box 1106, Folder 34)
    - "Carolyn Nyholm and Friends," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 1)
    - "Children's Defense Fund, Marian Wright Edelman," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 2)
    - "1. Corporate Responsibility, 2. Basic Board Orientation," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 3)
    - ENCOREplus Program
      - Training at Leadership Development Center,n.d.
        - Barbara Haber, Psychosocial Aspects of Breast Cancer, VHS * (Box 1107, Folder 4--5)
        - Fran Liggett, Group Dynamics, VHS * (Box 1107, Folder 6-7)
        - Joan Wagman, Budgeting and Administration of ENCORE Program, VHS * (Box 1107, Folder 8-10)
      - "Breast Cancer 1st edit segments: Anchorage, AK; Glendale, CA; Schenectady, NY," n.d., VHS (Box 1107, Folder 11)
      - "The CDC National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program," excerpt from television program 'Public Health Journal,' n.d., VHS (Box 1107, Folder 12)
      - ENCOREplus VNR and B-Roll, n.d., VHS (Box 1107, Folder 13)
    - "Fit for the Job," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 14)
    - "Girls Service Center, Istanbul, Elena R. Vergaria, Director," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 15)
    - "Glendora [Putnam] on Leadership," raw footage and edited master, n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 16-17)
    - "Gwen [Baker?] presentation," n.d. - Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 18)
    - Institute for Public Leadership
      - "The Campaign Works," Daryl Glenney, n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 19-20)
      - "Issues and Ethics in Campaign Communications," n.d., VHS (Box 1107, Folder 21)
      - "Political Workshop not shot at LDC," n.d., Umatic (Box 1107, Folder 22)
      - "Training Module with Daryl Glenney and Carol Whitney, Review and Comment on TV Spots," n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 1)
    - "Jean Tease(?) Edit, H. Vick, E. Anderson, J. Smith," n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 2)
    - "Jump" Public Service Announcement, n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 3)
    - "Leadership Summit," n.d., VHS (Box 1108, Folder 4)
    - MLK Holiday Commission, n.d.
      - Tapes 1-3, Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 5-7)
      - ISO camera, #2 and #4, Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 8-9)
      - Special Edit, Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 10)
      - Glendora Putnam, Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 11)
      - "3 min. Glendora Putnam at end," Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 12)
      - "Dr. King Rally, middle of tape," Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 13)
    - "Mock Board Mtg," n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 14-15)
    - "Modeling/Hair Styling," n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 16)
    - "Modeling/Dancing," n.d., Umatic (Box 1108, Folder 17)
    - "Multi-Cultural Panel Discussion," YWCA Leadership Development Center, n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 1)
    - "Peace Message," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 2-3)
    - "Racial Justice re: Blk Education," n.d. - Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 4)
    - St. Joseph [Missouri] Youth Alliance, "Working better together to benefit our children," YWCA is a member, n.d., VHS (Box 1109, Folder 5)
    - Stallard, Ann: Speech re membership, n.d., VHS (Box 1109, Folder 6)
    - "Strategic Planning Training Workshop, Synectics," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 7)
    - "Step Aerobic Outtakes," n.d., VHS (Box 1109, Folder 8)
    - "Take a Minute," Lifetime Television, Women's History Month series of spots with Dana King, featuring the YWCA and Prema Mathai Davis, n.d. [during Clinton administration], VHS (Box 1109, Folder 9)
    - "U.K. YWCA," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 19)
    - "Visioning the Future," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 11)
    - "YWCA Clips - Party, Meeting, recorded by Steve, Halloween, n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 12)
    - "YWCA is the Difference," n.d., VHS (Box 1109, Folder 13)
    - "YWCA Library/book footage," n.d., Beta (Box 1109, Folder 14)
    - "YWCA lunch in MPR w/Dr. Baker? speaking on Racial Issues," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 15)
    - "YWCA Media Coverage Compilation," n.d. [1990s], VHS (Box 1109, Folder 16)
    - "YWCA meeting, Betty Genne," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 17)
    - "YWCA Membership Video Freeze Frames," n.d., Umatic (Box 1109, Folder 18)
    - YWCA Promotional video by Silverman Productions, n.d. [after 1988 new logo], VHS (Box 1109, Folder 19)
    - "YWCA of Anchorage and Student YWCAs: Slide transfer, new YWCAS" n.d., Umatic (Box 1110, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified and undated videotapes
    - Raw footage Umatic tapes numbered 1-5, 7-10, 12, Umatic (Box 1110, Folder 2-11)
    - "Edit 2," Umatic (Box 1110, Folder 12)
    - Series of tapes numbered 1 through 13, #13 says "Exec Dir, Ellen, 49, 60, 65," Beta (Box 1110, Folder 13-24)
  - Videotapes--USE COPIES, [Use copies are numbered with the box and tape number of the original videotapes]
    - From box 1063 folder 4 - Faces of Racism, VHS, 1975 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1063 folder 5 - Understanding Institutional Racism, VHS, 1977 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1063 folder 7 - From Racism to Pluralism, VHS, 1978 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1063 folder 18 - Public Service Announcements featuring Lucille Ball, "Working," "Loneliness," and "Learning," VHS, 1983 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1063 folder 20 - Public Service Annoucements produced by Linc Services, Jewel Graham Interview, Lucille Ball Spots, and Action Spots, 1983, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1064 folder 18 - "YWCA 2000 A.D." and 3 Lucille Ball TV Spots, produced by Linc, Inc., VHS, Sep 1984 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1065 folder 14 - Middle East Encounter, VHS, 1985 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1065 folder 17-Career Volunteer Development Project, VHS, 1985 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1071 folder 1 - "It's Okay to Say No Way!" Teen Pregnancy Prevention Program music video, 1986, Master VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1071 folder 8 - "The National Support Plan for Community Associations," VHS, Aug 1986 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1071 folder 9 - Learning Center XX, Executive Management, VHS, Oct 1986 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1071 folder 14 - Soviet Women's Committee exchange trips, Women's Dialogue, USSR, VHS, n.d. (Box 1111)
    - From box 1071 folder 17 - "Probing PR," workshop with Sunshine Overkamp, VHS, Feb 1987 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1072 folder 3 - Young Women's Employment Training Project, 26 Apr 1987, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1073 folder 11 - Hearing on "Child Care Services for Job Corps," Panel 1, 23 Jul 1987, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1073 folder 16 - World Council Review (featuring LDC Peace Site Dedication), VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1073 folder 17 - Peace Site Dedication, Leadership Development Center, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1076 folder 4 - JobPlus: A Job Opportunity Partnership Program, Dayton, Ohio YWCA, VHS, Nov 1987 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1077 folder 8 and 10 - Convention Planning Meeting presentation, and "The YWCA as a Single Sex Organization," VHS, Mar 1988 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1079 folder 8-31st National Convention, 22-26 Jun 1988, Keynote address by Blandina Cardenas Ramirez, edited master, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1084 folder 6 - New Visual Identity for the YWCA of the USA, VHS, Jun 1988 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1084 folder 19 - "Crush," Teen discussion videos, VHS, 1989 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1084 folder 20 - "Lovesick," Teen discussion videos, VHS, 1989 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1085 folder 3 - "Faces In a Movement," Student YWCA, VHS, 1989 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1085 folder 5 - Tacoma YWCA Homeless School, segment in ABC News program "20/20," VHS, 20 Jan 1989 (Box 1111)
    - Oral Histories conducted at National Board Meeting in Phoenix, VHS, May 1989
      - From box 1085 folder 18 - Elizabeth Marti, Ellen Dammond, and Betty Genné interviewed by Adrienne Jones, 19 May 1989 (Box 1111)
      - From box 1085 folder 19 - Beth L. Moore [Elisabeth Luce Moore] (Box 1111)
      - From box 1085 folder 20 - Rosalie Oaks (Box 1111)
      - From box 1085 folder 21 - Elizabeth Palmer (Box 1111)
    - From box 1086 folder 15 - National Board Meeting at the Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Nonviolent Change, VHS, 5 Nov 1989 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1087 folder 5 - "Power of Vision," Charthouse Learning Corporation Discovering the Future Series re positive visions of the future, YWCA of the USA registration # 85167, 1990, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1087 folder 11 - Racial Justice Convocation, "Toward a Racial Justice Agenda for the 21st Century," 2-4 Feb 1990, News clip, KPHO-TV 5, Phoenix, VHS, 3 Feb (Box 1111)
    - From box 1087 folder 15 - Racial Justice Convocation, "Toward a Racial Justice Agenda for the 21st Century," 2-4 Feb 1990, Highlights, VHS (Box 1111)
    - From box 1088 folder 11 - "The Purpose Study Session" with Marilyn Whaley Winters, Chair, Committee to Study the Purpose, for use in local discussion sessions, edited version, VHS, 30 Jun 1990 (Box 1111)
    - From box 1088 folder 13 - Swearing in of Gwendolyn Baker as NY City School Board President (?), VHS, 31 Jul 1990 (Box 1111)